Graeme Maciver

Full Stack Engineer

linkedin.com/in/graememaciver in github.com/isnotahippy (7)

Skills

GraemeMaciver.com



Personal Statement

I am a London based software engineer with 5+ years of experience, which includes 3 years freelancing, multiple start up projects, side projects, 3 months in India and 1 year working alongside the world's leading marketing agencies. I walk the line between front and backend engineer with a creative head and a commitment to efficient well architected solutions.

Work Experience

Cohaesus

March 2012 - Present

I have been with Cohaesus since March 2012 building the technical side of digital campaigns for some of the worlds largest marketing agencies. Cohaesus remains platform agnostic, which exposes our team to lots of technologies and environments. My role here extends beyond the software engineering. I am responsible for the day to day running of projects and our outsourced teams, a point of contact for our clients, regularly attending client meetings and act as lead developer. I work as a full stack engineer, getting involved in all areas of the application life cycle.

Freelance Web Developer

2008 - 2012

While studying in Glasgow I was also freelancing. Over 3 years I built up a modest client base and provided website builds for small businesses. Managing my own clients and projects was a great experience and I gained valuable skills that I apply daily in my current position.

TheBookPond.com

2009 - 2011

Also during university I built a website aimed at pairing students looking to sell textbooks with students looking to buy. The site gained attention on campuses across the UK, was featured by BBC Click and Pocketlint.com. In the end we couldn't quite beat the on campus book stores, though we learned a lot during the attempt. The site exposed me to some of the legalities of collecting data, protecting users, and marketing online.

Shields Automotive Ltd

April 2011 - Jan 2012

During 2011 as Shields were transitioning between locations I aided as a consultant and technical support for their IT infrastructure. This involved extra

Volunteering

Shelter Associates

In 2011 I lived and worked in Pune, India for 3 months. I was working with Shelter Associates, supported by EWB-UK. Shelter are an NGO who work to improve the lives of slum dwellers in Maharashtra. Part of this work involves collecting data regarding the population of slums in Pune and surrounding areas through surveying. While with Shelter I worked on their survey data system, and created a diverse CMS capable of handling large amounts of documentation, media and articles from Shelter's projects. This was a great experience which helped build my skills as a software engineer by being wholly responsible for the architecture, project management and technical outputs of the project.

Engineers Without Borders UK

Since taking part in the Shelter Associates placement I have continued to volunteer with EWB-UK in a few roles. For the second year I will be managing an EWB-UK placement, overseeing other volunteers while they are abroad and helping them set up their placement. Along with this I have been consulting with EWB-UK on various IT projects, and have developed the ICE Toolkit (www.engineers.org.uk). Whilst volunteering with EWB-UK I have gained experience in interviewing candidates, project management, and exposure to the world of international development.

Qualifications

Polyglot

I seek to remain platform agnostic, keeping an open mind and exposing myself to as many languages and technologies as possible. I am always open to change and learning from others.